<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-21T21:22:26-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Queer Auntie</title><subtitle>The blog of writer Regina Clarkinia</subtitle><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Museum at F.I.T.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/museum/The-Museum-at-F.I.T/html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Museum at F.I.T." /><published>2018-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/museum/The-Museum-at-F.I.T/The-Museum-at-F.I.T.</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/museum/The-Museum-at-F.I.T/html">&lt;p&gt;Late April. Around 5:30pm. I’m walking down the street to a see a museum show about high fashion for different body types. Right out in public, in the middle of busy Manhattan, a class of bootcampers side-shuffle from one side of the one-lane street to the other. At any moment, a car could drive through them, or want to drive through them. The instructor shouts commands in a heavy New York accent. I imagined he had been a fire fighter or a cop who survived 9-11 and couldn’t work the job anymore due to PTSD. He decided on a career change: to use his aggressive tenacity to motivate 20-somethings into shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest slackers, a tall beefy gay man and two straight women, entertained each other in muffled comments and exaggerated reactions to the drills, theatrically expressing how tired they were. Most everyone wore yoga style sleeveless T-shirts (the kind that hang like the top of a toga). The bootcamp’s motto was printed on the shirts, something like, “This ain’t no joke”. A good reminder that physical fitness is a matter of life or death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a bench on the promenade outside the Fashion Institute for Technology, to join the other gawkers. Lounging on benches in the mellow sun, about fifty of us stared expressionlessly at the bootcamp spectacle. One guy even had his camera up. It was quality footage for a 10-second snap, gram, tweet or meme-thing, just because of how bold it was to face the humiliation of constant onlookers. After the class did a bunch of squats in the only section of the street not parked in, the instructor indicated that it was now time to jog. They ran off in a line like ducklings, the slackers at the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed them down the block, into the fancy glass-walled lobby of The Museum at FIT. An indoors red carpet leads to the entrance of the museum, but for some reason it was cordoned off with movie theater velvet ropes. I went to walk around. A security guard sitting at a podium on my right suddenly asked me what I wanted and I said to see the museum. Security guards and doormen exist in every New York lobby. But they don’t necessarily greet you. They wait to see what you do. They are there to test peoples’ certitude. Are you in the right place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum is one long room, shaped like the letter L. If it was a golf course it would be called a dog leg, dimly lit. Clothing is displayed on dressing forms on a platform that runs along the walls on either side. You walk down the center, with clothing displays to your right and left. It’s like you’re on a catwalk and the fashions are looking at you! Several of us were smartly dressed. A businesslike woman wore red stockings, a pair of ladies had hats and me with the weird side burns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The red stockings woman spent a lot of time with each piece of clothing, probably reading every single placard, like I did, and always have since I could read and go to museums. Isn’t Delmonico’s a thing? I would like to go there with this 60-year-old woman and have a steak and wine and talk about the weather and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eavesdropped on the hat-wearing pair of women. One listened. The other spoke in Spanglish. Quick to judge. Theatrically editorializing on the Donna Karan shoulder pads dress. Loves Donna Karan. Owns a DK couture thing which makes her say the name, Donna Karan, with familiarity. Spoke disparagingly of Rei Kawakubo, which even though RK is my favorite, I totally get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kawakubo Dress. This dress is from the 1980s show called “Body Meet Dress. Dress Meet Body.” Form-fitting. Stretchy material. With lumps of stuffing here and there in unexpected places like the hip or arm or anywhere. If one can have shoulder pads or a bustle on the butt, then why not enhancements in other places. Reminds me of Bouffon outfits, which makes sense because Kawakubo is often mocking the ignorance of fashion norms and ridiculous standards for what a female body is supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were so many guards, it felt like overkill. But then, it’s in the middle of Manhattan where a zillion people are doing whatever they want everywhere. You never know who might walk, jog or side-shuffle in. The guards, noticeably gentlemanly and wonderfully adept at containing being stir-crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not far from the Kawakubo dress is a package of Spanx. Across from the Kawakubo dress, an actual bustle is on display. Posterior is the word for butt here. There are also different variations on corsets and girdles on display, including a pregnant woman’s corset and a little girl corset. There was also a pregnant woman’s isolation cloak, for when women were meant to quarantine themselves during their unsightly pregnancies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dress from the 1960s with plastic windows down the sides reveals the body, and the show description infers that the woman wouldn’t wear anything underneath a dress like this. The dress had the Courreges futuristic antiseptic but playful stiffness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clothing designs had to do with women covering up their bodies, until the 1960s when clothes revealed parts of the body in cheeky places. When fashion required women to show more skin, exercise replaced bustles and corsets as the method of forming the body. The Museum at FIT has a video looping Olivia Newton-John’s “Let’s Get Physical” as well as a workout video from the 1980s blared upbeat music and instructions while women in pastel leotards and leg warmers followed along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens when you don’t wear the bras, spanks or work out obsessively? One of my favorite runway photos of all time is Liza Minelli at like 2014 Oscars wearing a bright blue limpid silk Halston pantsuit with no bra. It was very unpopular with the press. But Tumblr loved it and so did I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Mary looking for a place to give birth to Jesus Christ, Leslie Jones could not find a designer for the Ghostbusters premiere in 2016. Jones tweeted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s so funny how there are no designers wanting to help me with a premiere dress for movie. Hmmm that will change and I remember everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until Christian Soriano leapt at the chance to have Leslie Jones as a client. He designed a beautiful red dress, now on display the The FIT Museum. When people applauded his choice, Siriano tweeted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It shouldn’t be exceptional to work with brilliant people just because they’re not sample size. Congrats aren’t in order, a change is.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Museum" /><category term="Body Image" /><category term="Fashion" /><category term="Femme" /><summary type="html">Late April. Around 5:30pm. I’m walking down the street to a see a museum show about high fashion for different body types. Right out in public, in the middle of busy Manhattan, a class of bootcampers side-shuffle from one side of the one-lane street to the other. At any moment, a car could drive through them, or want to drive through them. The instructor shouts commands in a heavy New York accent. I imagined he had been a fire fighter or a cop who survived 9-11 and couldn’t work the job anymore due to PTSD. He decided on a career change: to use his aggressive tenacity to motivate 20-somethings into shape.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22physical.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Olivia%20Newton-John/%20Physical%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6zwPVU92-XQ%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sugar Hill Museum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/museum/Sugar-Hill-Museum.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sugar Hill Museum" /><published>2018-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/museum/Sugar-Hill-Museum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/museum/Sugar-Hill-Museum.html">&lt;p&gt;The Sugar Hill Museum, in the Sugar Hill neighborhood of Harlem, is full of interactive materials. Raw wood sticks with frayed bark in a horizontal built-in shelf, some just lying there, others in a natural fiber basket. They seem like props for kids to generate stories and I wondered how it worked. Same with the living room-sized chess board on the floor with toddler-sized chess pieces in the central open gallery space. Keeping track of any chess game would result in a story structure, since it has relationship, motivation, strategy to pull that off with devastating losses and smug victories, and every emotion in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There weren’t kids using the space when I was there, but The Sugar Hill Museum is a place for groups of kids to move, play, roll up their sleeves and activate their voices. I arrived at the front door wet from a misty rain and my own sweat. The eye liner from my eyes had drooped down to below my eyes, like a 1980s football quarterback, but I didn’t know this yet. The guy at the front was very friendly and we talked about the woes of gentrification and lots of other choir preaching tidbits. They weren’t usually open on Wednesday, so the galleries were pretty empty. It was just me an a security guard and I had to be let in to one of the galleries that was still locked. That’s how dead it was. But I could hear their screams and running feet. That’s how lucky I felt to be avoiding noisy kid mobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You enter the museum by walking down blonde wood stairs that lead to a central gallery, a high-ceilinged, open, versatile space, with that barn-sized chess game in the middle. To the right of the entrance, built-in risers offer audience seating in seven giant wood stairs. A show of mural-sized pieces designed by two of the curatorial staff cover the walls. The graphic design prints showcase blown-up historical photos of Sugar Hill residents in action, connecting and making things together. Each photo mirrors itself to create a kaleidoscope look, that gives the impression that people who share their stories accordion their worlds outward to supply the rest of the neighborhood with energy to grow together from within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This central gallery leads to two main galleries, and on the opposite side is a sloping corridor. One wall of the corridor is those sticks are that I was talking about. The other side of the corridor is a glass facade that opens into separate studio labs for kids and one artist-in-residence studio, which is bursting with flowing black ink on different white surfaces, from drawings on crumpled papers to a flat drawing of of a kid slumped over a swing, belly-down, like a rag on a kitchen sink spigot, you know how you used to do. The kids studios are full of inviting stations made for kids to tell their story in their own way, like if NPR’s recording studios were actual playgrounds. The stations seem to beckon the children, “Come hither and try to break me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two different shows in the main galleries. One is a room dedicated to Ana Mendieta’s projects with children. It was just the security guard and me, trying to be polite and friendly one another. I am a fan of Ana Mendieta, a Cuban American performance artist whose life was tragically cut short, allegedly murdered by her husband, allegedly also an artist. But this is about Ana Mendieta’s art and the way that she worked with children in a way that avoided leading questions and gave them the keys to the creative car. On the left side, a black and white wide-shot video she took of a class-size group of elementary school students playing together, with a full-size parachute, you know the game. Along the right and back walls, hung low to ground, kid-height, are photos of Mendieta with an abundance of facial hair glued to her face to create a Mario/Luigi-style mustache. In the back left corner is a listening nook, with a stool, two speakers and thoughtful and joyous kids voices talking about what they believe a soul to be in terms of time. The voices rev up then slow down like a car changing gears unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum’s description on the wall of the Ana Mendieta show says: “In this exhibition children are encouraged to reflect on notions of power and freedom through verbal and physical exploration.” This is the repeated theme throughout the museum and it got me thinking about how exploring thoughts and critical expression through physical activity, thinking in your body, and in a shared space, may be the best and only way to “reflect on notions of power and freedom”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the museum, the idea of producing a story isn’t confronted directly. Kids are courted into choosing to invent stories by accident, as a by-product of play. The show that is up in the other space takes the taboo of forcing kids to write, learn and produce, and instead of avoiding it, this show amplifies the tension to a game based on a new folkloric character. The Bibliobandido shows up in town once a month and extracts stories from the children. He’s like the Tooth Fairy, but with a spooky, mysterious, menacing, even threatening quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bibliobandido was co-created in a town in Honduras that artist, Marisa Jahn, was asked to help design a creative program to help increase child literacy. Before you go in, you take a battery-operated candle and you watch a video with kids from Honduras who have to contend with the Bibliobandido. They tell the stories that they have given to the Bibliobandido, whose gaunt, stylish roll, loping in on a horse, wearing a hat that covers their eyes and a poncho that covers their body. The Bibliobandido can be a woman one month, a man or a gender-fluid person the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The room is painted from floor to ceiling. Kids can write their own stories to save their lives on a short, kid-size table in the center of the room. When you leave the room, you tell your story through a hole in the wall, then hand over your candle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Time passing and change are undeniable aspects of the world around us…Often artistic creation results in the production of art objects. However, when a concern for time is primary, an experience not an object may result.” -Ana Mendieta&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Ana Mendieta quote, included on the wall of the show, speaks to how playing doesn’t always yield a physical object, other than the experience itself. And got me to thinking about the difference between creating work to be consumed versus the act of creative expression. Writing a script versus the moment of performing it. Having a gorgeous latte without sharing it on Instagram. Reminds me of doing “devised work”, a physical theater piece that is created collaboratively, “on its feet” rather than written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sugar Hill Museum facilitates play that doesn’t worry about yielding an object, such as a good story. I know how hard it can be to tell a story, especially when I want it to be good, or if I’m worried if people will like it, or if I feel like I don’t want to because I only want to tell stories on accident as a result of being with people, goofing off having fun. I love to generate new work, but the thing I fear is making it make sense with a clear statement, sharing it in the world and then being ridiculed. But if it’s do or die, as in the beautiful Bibliobandido will terrorize my family unless I speak a story through a make-believe conduit in some dry wall, then I will get the shit done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Be intent on action,&lt;br /&gt;
not on the fruits of action;&lt;br /&gt;
avoid attraction to the fruits&lt;br /&gt;
and attachment to inaction!”&lt;br /&gt;
— Bhagavad Gita, Translated by Barbara Stoler Miller&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Museum" /><category term="Storytelling" /><category term="Kids" /><summary type="html">The Sugar Hill Museum, in the Sugar Hill neighborhood of Harlem, is full of interactive materials. Raw wood sticks with frayed bark in a horizontal built-in shelf, some just lying there, others in a natural fiber basket. They seem like props for kids to generate stories and I wondered how it worked. Same with the living room-sized chess board on the floor with toddler-sized chess pieces in the central open gallery space. Keeping track of any chess game would result in a story structure, since it has relationship, motivation, strategy to pull that off with devastating losses and smug victories, and every emotion in the book.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22mendieta.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Ana%20Mendieta/%20Untitled%20(Facial%20Hair%20Transplants),%201972.%20%C2%A9%20The%20Estate%20of%20Ana%20Mendieta%20Collection,%20LLC.%20Courtesy%20Galerie%20Lelong%20&amp;%20Co.%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22http://www.galerielelong.com/%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Town Cats</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/poetry/Town-Cats.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Town Cats" /><published>2018-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/poetry/Town-Cats</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/poetry/Town-Cats.html">&lt;p&gt;Town Cats who &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; to own the turf.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s a jukebox of kittens.&lt;br /&gt;
They pee on the mats. Perfume!&lt;br /&gt;
Now that’s the ticket.&lt;br /&gt;
They &lt;strong&gt;start&lt;/strong&gt; to fight the House Cat.&lt;br /&gt;
The big owner invades!&lt;br /&gt;
They pee and have sex. Feline Infection!&lt;br /&gt;
They &lt;strong&gt;realize&lt;/strong&gt; they don’t mind the cars, that much anyways.&lt;br /&gt;
If they &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt; only &lt;strong&gt;get&lt;/strong&gt; Tommy to &lt;strong&gt;stop trying&lt;/strong&gt; an insurrection.&lt;br /&gt;
Bass drum. High hat. Scratch. Crash! Ride.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Poetry" /><category term="Music" /><category term="Cats" /><summary type="html">Town Cats who want to own the turf. It’s a jukebox of kittens. They pee on the mats. Perfume! Now that’s the ticket. They start to fight the House Cat. The big owner invades! They pee and have sex. Feline Infection! They realize they don’t mind the cars, that much anyways. If they can only get Tommy to stop trying an insurrection. Bass drum. High hat. Scratch. Crash! Ride.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22towncats.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Creative%20Commons/%20%E7%81%B0%E7%81%B0%E5%A6%88%20Wei%20Wei%20Ma%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22http://blog.sina.com.cn/xy541107%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">When It’s Just Dark</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/poetry/When-It-s-Just-Dark.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When It’s Just Dark" /><published>2018-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/poetry/When-It%E2%80%99s-Just-Dark</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/poetry/When-It-s-Just-Dark.html">&lt;p&gt;Sheets of hot tin roof go “waeahwaehhhweeaahhh,” a shimmering saw. Fleet-footed. A piece of cake pulled from the one cooling in the windah. Crumblings onto the unlit grass shards. Running through backyards in just the 1950s just a boy with a slingshot in yer pocket sayin’ “gee whiz” the neck snaps back, trachea bent into a dent by a cotton cord not always strung with clothes usually but not always. His birthright chances scatter like cat-eyes, surround where his spine lies. Their glassy flecks currying God-given favors, oven lives, clotheslines, boy oh boy cake freaks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Poetry" /><category term="Noir" /><category term="Olden Days" /><category term="Boyhood" /><summary type="html">Sheets of hot tin roof go “waeahwaehhhweeaahhh,” a shimmering saw. Fleet-footed. A piece of cake pulled from the one cooling in the windah. Crumblings onto the unlit grass shards. Running through backyards in just the 1950s just a boy with a slingshot in yer pocket sayin’ “gee whiz” the neck snaps back, trachea bent into a dent by a cotton cord not always strung with clothes usually but not always. His birthright chances scatter like cat-eyes, surround where his spine lies. Their glassy flecks currying God-given favors, oven lives, clotheslines, boy oh boy cake freaks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22clothesline.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Creative%20Commons/%20Flickr%20Mike%20Bitzenhofer%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22https://www.flickr.com/photos/tambako/4750603032/%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">God’s Back (Again)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/comedy/Commandments.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="God’s Back (Again)" /><published>2018-03-18T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/comedy/Commandments</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/comedy/Commandments.html">&lt;p&gt;“Hey there believers, it’s Angel Rafael here, with another vlog post. This time I’m in The Brooklyn Public Library. It’s the middle of the night. I was sent here to deliver these stone tablets with news from this one god named Rebenca. She’s the one who helps you get tax breaks out of the blue. And avoid meter maids. One time she made a meter maid trip and fall while he was ticketing a person who just lost their job. That Rebenca! She watches soaps and drinks whiskey sours all day. Then goes on walks through the galactic rainforest. Rebenca helped write three of the original commandments. Oh and she gives out EXTRA GOOD multiple orgasms to everyone, male or female, who is pure of heart. She throws parties every time the moons 3 galaxies away get full, which is most months. Oh Rebenca! Always wears these wild purple velvet gowns with three gemstones dangling on each shoulder pad. This week it’s rubies.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Rebenca wants you to know that the human race will continue to be punished with another Fifty Shades book AND movie every year as long as people keep having this problem with sexual consent. But, on a positive note, Rebenca gave you four new commandments to help y’all out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h7&gt;1st COMMANDMENT: Straight boys, thou shalt not gas light by candle light.&lt;/h7&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;When you treat a basicky hipster to a night of candle-lit wining and dining, they’ll be expecting rose petals and a day in Paris. They’ll be shocked when treated like a pet in the home of a curious toddler. But you already knew that, didn’t you? Or didn’t you? Or did you? Or, didn’t you? Or didn’t you? Or did you? Or, didn’t you?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Or didn’t you? Or did you? Or, didn’t you? That’s how it is with this gaslighting malarkey. Only god knows and her name is Rebenca. It’s like you think you can hide, but then there’s a trailer for Fifty Shades before every single movie - even art movies, indy comedies, no matter the demographic. Next commandment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h7&gt;2nd COMMANDMENT: Straight boys, thou shalt have sex with your bros.&lt;/h7&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;It’s obvious you love each other. You know that one guy, you know the one… and you know what? It doesn’t make you gay to fuck him. Brokeback Mountain was made by an all straight cast, writers and director, so you don’t have to be gay in order to claim gay shit.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I mean, it would be so hot if you two would just fuck. Give AND receive at least once in your life or you’ll plateau. But I mean take all this with a grain of salt because a word of caution - both Rebenca and I have a fatal flaw where we are queer and think everyone else is queer deep down. And that’s just plain wrong. Yet, my errant notions are not what is currently causing god’s wrath: the sex misery currently clogging up social media is the problem. Rebenca is bothered. And you don’t want to know when she gets very bothered. She goes hard. Listen to Rebenca’s next commandment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h7&gt;3rd COMMANDMENT: To ye all, femme and/or masc, thou shalt talk about what you like and dislike before, during and after sex.&lt;/h7&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Talking about what you’re into doesn’t ruin the moment. Know what you might want to do on your date and know what you absolutely will not do. What you want to do is not the same as what your date must do. Ask your date what they want. Tell them what you want.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Even Fifty Shades gets that right probably. I haven’t seen any of the movies. None of us have. Just the trailers. Is it just queers, angels, demons and other supernatural creatures who can’t stand the Fifty Shades franchise? We haven’t truly considered that narrow-minded individuals might actually like Fifty Shades. It’s possible that Rebenca’s punishment may not be a punishment after all. It’s like when we ejected Adam and Eve from the garden: these things backfire on us sometimes. But I mean. Nah. Fifty Shades is literally a dull porno made by cutting clips from the sad parts of a pharmaceutical commercial. Yeah, it’s a decent enough punishment that should effect change. Yeah. OK! So final commandment. And this one - I think it sucks. If I’m being honest, this one is just Rebenca making some shit up and hoping it sticks. It’s kind of like two commandments… but it’s not even a commandment like technically. I’m just asking that you don’t shoot the messenger.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h7&gt;4th COMMANDMENT: And for ye femmes, thou shalt not be so nice.&lt;/h7&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;When going on a date, try sporting a confident, devil-may-care attitude. For femmes, the threat of being potentially tacitly under threat of a crime that is only prosecuted 1% of the time, it can be hard to feel as freewheeling as the masculine types who may never have felt threatened. Try to get into the headspace that you don’t live in a society where 1 in 6 women are victims of rape and attempted rape. You’ll find it’s a fun escape from reality. I know that’s a lot of fictionalizing, but for those of you who are good at make-believing when you’re being gaslit: why not apply your superpower to your own sexual gratification.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know I said, God, you are mean. Also maybe not so much stats. And then Rebenca was like, but they don’t believe in anything that isn’t evidence-based. So, she won that argument. Rebenca wins every argument, being the most usually drunk and stubborn being I have ever met. But at least she’s not a borderline criminal. Anyhow, I wanted to make this one more fun like it should be so let’s switch gears a lot now.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Guess what!? It’s time to play, ladeez! Turn the tables with a some silly lady shenanigans for once!? Amiright ladeez!? Play dress up by returning from the bathroom with a metal probe and actual shit in your hair. Your man will be attentive while pretending not to be weirded out. In other words, take control. Go gurl and other aphorisms popularized by Pinterest &amp;amp; Instagram and ruinously emblazoned on otherwise perfectly fine T-shirts at ROSS Dress for Less. You know what I’m talking about my biatches and bashes and beeshies my beastlettes!’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I realize I’m not very relatable; I’m an angel. I’m here to deliver these commandments, which, I told Rebenca, is so Old Testament in a world where even the New Testament is tired. The one new thing we have is ignorant and outdated. And most people don’t even believe in anything unless it’s in the form of a popular meme. And here I am delivering stone tablets made out of stone with writing that was chiseled into them with chisels. Google stores every last tidbit we do on the internet, but one good bulldozing and these laws are toast, I told Rebenca. I’ll just leave these here, at the reference desk at the Brooklyn Public Library. You can’t check them out, but you can look at them. Maybe check the Library’s twitter feed. It should be a big deal for them. Sheesh, let’s hope it is. In closing, change your non-consensual ways, while there’s still time. Melania is currently hard at work ghost writing the next Fifty Shades franchise, but it doesn’t have to be this way. It has been decreed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poster: For basic ladies who considered S&amp;amp;M when the Kirkland is enough.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Comedy" /><category term="Fiction" /><category term="Consensual" /><category term="Auntie" /><summary type="html">“Hey there believers, it’s Angel Rafael here, with another vlog post. This time I’m in The Brooklyn Public Library. It’s the middle of the night. I was sent here to deliver these stone tablets with news from this one god named Rebenca. She’s the one who helps you get tax breaks out of the blue. And avoid meter maids. One time she made a meter maid trip and fall while he was ticketing a person who just lost their job. That Rebenca! She watches soaps and drinks whiskey sours all day. Then goes on walks through the galactic rainforest. Rebenca helped write three of the original commandments. Oh and she gives out EXTRA GOOD multiple orgasms to everyone, male or female, who is pure of heart. She throws parties every time the moons 3 galaxies away get full, which is most months. Oh Rebenca! Always wears these wild purple velvet gowns with three gemstones dangling on each shoulder pad. This week it’s rubies.’</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22holytabs.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Five Alive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fiction/Five-Alive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five Alive" /><published>2018-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fiction/Five-Alive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fiction/Five-Alive.html">&lt;p&gt;When Lucia saw the one where Bugs cut carrots into his own cauldron, the one he was being cooked in, she went to the kitchen and got a bag of carrots from the bottom drawer of the fridge and a knife from the wooden silverware drawer. On the sofa, she cut the carrots into disks and pretended to be boiled alive while singing like Bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucia was five, her favorite number. Her next birthday loomed large. Every day she worried that she wasn’t going to be able to hack it as a six-year-old. She would wake up at the break of dawn to be alone and watch Looney Tunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucia watched Bugs Bunny caught in a cauldron of rabbit stew, singing at the top of his lungs while acting like he was bathing in a luxurious hot tub. Bugs’s boyish mirth conflicted with the reality of his dire circumstances. He didn’t express fear or pain - a defensive tactic that threw off his captors. If it didn’t give him the upper hand, at least it dampened the pleasure they got from hurting him. Most of the cartoons with Bugs bathing in his own stew were overtly and covertly racist. Like almost all media in American history, it tacitly supported the terrorism that kept whites in power. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/qZWD5RM67rZfi/giphy.gif&quot;&gt;“All this and Rabbit Stew”&lt;/a&gt; a blackface version of Elmer Fudd ineptly tries to get Bugs. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kS6ksEyO_l8&quot;&gt;“Wackiki Wabbit”&lt;/a&gt; a couple of escaped convicts try to cook Bugs while lampooning Pacific Islander traditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the back yard grass Lucia would brush her attack dog’s teeth. And she would pick boysenberries off the overgrown bush in the backyard while keeping an eye peeled for rats that ran from palm tree skirt to palm tree skirt via the phone wires. When Lucia would notice a rat glide by on the wire there was nothing she could do but it felt like knowing helped even if to avoid being seen. She could create a magical forcefield, fashioned out of her stunned fear. And there’s the fact that being fore-warned about creepy things helps you to be less traumatized when they do strike. But the rats always kept their distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At night the men would share important-seeming chatter about the dangers of the rats and the men influenced one another to hire other, apartment-dwelling men to cut the palms bare to clear the rats’ nests. The rats were a nuisance to the neighborhood and threatened the safety and cleanliness that people who live in the suburbs look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was 1982 and Mommie Dearest was broadcast on TV. Finding it too adult and boring, Lucia gulped down the horribleness of it anyways. She gawked at it while pretending not to watch. Children crave campy violence since it mirrors the behind-closed-doors social interactions that aren’t openly acknowledged, and the actual subconscious leverage between people. Children eavesdrop on their parent’s fights. Like tea leaf readers they look for signs in the nonsense for what their futures hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Black family lived in her house before Lucia and her white family moved in. Her father got a deal on the house because white people overtly and covertly put a lower price on houses owned by Blacks. He considered this purchase to be a sign that he was a great negotiator as well as… well, not quite an abolitionist, but pretty close. Even though he used racial slurs and spoke condescendingly towards non-whites, he thought that he was very open-minded and sympatheitic for buying a home at below cost from a Black family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the palm trunks were cut naked by the poorer men, the rats moved into the English ivy that was smothering the wooden fence. Before the rats had to move from their nests in the crispy palm fronds, Lucia kept vigilant watch for them. She brushed her dog’s teeth in the manner of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sgkYHhG18uc&quot;&gt;a recurring video short on Sesame Street of a city dentist who brushed a llama’s teeth.&lt;/a&gt; Except Lucia had a collection of twigs rather than professional dental tools. Neither the llama nor her dog wanted to have a person doing things to their mouth even if it was labeled as being for their own good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She watched the Secret of Nimh at her grandmother’s house two years later in 1984. Her grandmother kept her eyebrows well-arched and went to church frequently and stopped to give cash to drifters but berated the men she lived with. The Secret of Nimh was a boring and unsettling cartoon and was too grown-up for a kid to consume like cereal on Saturday morning. It was something a child secretly kept tabs on. Lucia absorbed it like her safety depended on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/qZWD5RM67rZfi/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Fiction" /><category term="Noir" /><category term="TV" /><category term="Cartoons" /><summary type="html">When Lucia saw the one where Bugs cut carrots into his own cauldron, the one he was being cooked in, she went to the kitchen and got a bag of carrots from the bottom drawer of the fridge and a knife from the wooden silverware drawer. On the sofa, she cut the carrots into disks and pretended to be boiled alive while singing like Bugs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22llama-4.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Creative%20Commons/%20Flickr%20Tambako%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22https://www.flickr.com/photos/tambako/4750603032/%22%7D" /></entry></feed>