<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-20T20:18:55-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Regina Clarkinia</title><subtitle>Stories, Visuals and Ideas</subtitle><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><entry><title type="html">Five Alive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fiction/Five-Alive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five Alive" /><published>2017-12-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fiction/Five-Alive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fiction/Five-Alive.html">&lt;p&gt;When Lucia saw the one where Bugs cut carrots into his own cauldron, the one he was being cooked in, she went to the kitchen and got a bag of carrots from the bottom drawer of the fridge and a knife from the wooden silverware drawer. On the sofa, she cut the carrots into disks and pretended to be boiled alive while singing like Bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucia was five, her favorite number. Her next birthday loomed large. Every day she worried that she wasn’t going to be able to hack it as a six-year-old. She would wake up at the break of dawn to be alone and watch Looney Tunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucia watched Bugs Bunny caught in a cauldron of rabbit stew, singing at the top of his lungs while acting like he was bathing in a luxurious hot tub. Bugs’s boyish mirth conflicted with the reality of his dire circumstances. He didn’t express fear or pain - a defensive tactic that threw off his captors. If it didn’t give him the upper hand, at least it dampened the pleasure they got from hurting him. Most of the cartoons with Bugs bathing in his own stew were overtly and covertly racist. Like almost all media in American history, it tacitly supported the terrorism that kept whites in power. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/qZWD5RM67rZfi/giphy.gif&quot;&gt;“All this and Rabbit Stew”&lt;/a&gt; a blackface version of Elmer Fudd ineptly tries to get Bugs. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kS6ksEyO_l8&quot;&gt;“Wackiki Wabbit”&lt;/a&gt; a couple of escaped convicts try to cook Bugs while lampooning Pacific Islander traditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the back yard grass Lucia would brush her attack dog’s teeth. And she would pick boysenberries off the overgrown bush in the backyard while keeping an eye peeled for rats that ran from palm tree skirt to palm tree skirt via the phone wires. When Lucia would notice a rat glide by on the wire there was nothing she could do but it felt like knowing helped even if to avoid being seen. She could create a magical forcefield, fashioned out of her stunned fear. And there’s the fact that being fore-warned about creepy things helps you to be less traumatized when they do strike. But the rats always kept their distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At night the men would share important-seeming chatter about the dangers of the rats and the men influenced one another to hire other, apartment-dwelling men to cut the palms bare to clear the rats’ nests. The rats were a nuisance to the neighborhood and threatened the safety and cleanliness that people who live in the suburbs look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was 1982 and Mommie Dearest was broadcast on TV. Finding it too adult and boring, Lucia gulped down the horribleness of it anyways. She gawked at it while pretending not to watch. Children crave campy violence since it mirrors the behind-closed-doors social interactions that aren’t openly acknowledged, and the actual subconscious leverage between people. Children eavesdrop on their parent’s fights. Like tea leaf readers they look for signs in the nonsense for what their futures hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Black family lived in her house before Lucia and her white family moved in. Her father got a deal on the house because white people overtly and covertly put a lower price on houses owned by Blacks. He considered this purchase to be a sign that he was a great negotiator as well as… well, not quite an abolitionist, but pretty close. Even though he used racial slurs and spoke condescendingly towards non-whites, he thought that he was very open-minded and sympatheitic for buying a home at below cost from a Black family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the palm trunks were cut naked by the poorer men, the rats moved into the English ivy that was smothering the wooden fence. Before the rats had to move from their nests in the crispy palm fronds, Lucia kept vigilant watch for them. She brushed her dog’s teeth in the manner of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sgkYHhG18uc&quot;&gt;a recurring video short on Sesame Street of a city dentist who brushed a llama’s teeth.&lt;/a&gt; Except Lucia had a collection of twigs rather than professional dental tools. Neither the llama nor her dog wanted to have a person doing things to their mouth even if it was labeled as being for their own good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She watched the Secret of Nimh at her grandmother’s house two years later in 1984. Her grandmother kept her eyebrows well-arched and went to church frequently and stopped to give cash to drifters but berated the men she lived with. The Secret of Nimh was a boring and unsettling cartoon and was too grown-up for a kid to consume like cereal on Saturday morning. It was something a child secretly kept tabs on. Lucia absorbed it like her safety depended on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/qZWD5RM67rZfi/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="TV" /><category term="Cartoons" /><summary type="html">When Lucia saw the one where Bugs cut carrots into his own cauldron, the one he was being cooked in, she went to the kitchen and got a bag of carrots from the bottom drawer of the fridge and a knife from the wooden silverware drawer. On the sofa, she cut the carrots into disks and pretended to be boiled alive while singing like Bugs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22llama-4.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Creative%20Commons/%20Flickr%20Tambako%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22https://www.flickr.com/photos/tambako/4750603032/%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">God’s Back (Again)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/comedy/Commandments.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="God’s Back (Again)" /><published>2017-01-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/comedy/Commandments</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/comedy/Commandments.html">&lt;p&gt;“Hey there believers, it’s Angel Rafael here, with another vlog post. This time I’m in The Brooklyn Public Library. It’s the middle of the night. I was sent here to deliver these stone tablets with news from this one god named Rebenca. She’s the one who helps you get tax breaks out of the blue. And avoid meter maids. One time she made a meter maid trip and fall while he was ticketing a person who just lost their job. That Rebenca! She watches soaps and drinks whiskey sours all day. Then goes on walks through the galactic rainforest. Rebenca helped write three of the original commandments. Oh and she gives out EXTRA GOOD multiple orgasms to everyone, male or female, who is pure of heart. She throws parties every time the moons 3 galaxies away get full, which is most months. Oh Rebenca! Always wears these wild purple velvet gowns with three gemstones dangling on each shoulder pad. This week it’s rubies.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Rebenca wants you to know that the human race will continue to be punished with another Fifty Shades book AND movie every year as long as people keep having this problem with sexual consent. But, on a positive note, Rebenca gave you four new commandments to help y’all out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FIRST NEW COMMANDMENT: Thou shalt not gas light by candle light.
When you treat a basicky hipster to a night of candle-lit wining and dining, they’ll be expecting rose petals and a day in Paris. They’ll be shocked when treated like a pet in the home of a curious toddler. But you already knew that, didn’t you? Or didn’t you? Or did you? Or, didn’t you? Or didn’t you? Or did you? Or, didn’t you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Or didn’t you? Or did you? Or, didn’t you? That’s how it is with this gaslighting malarkey. Only god knows and her name is Rebenca. It’s like you think you can hide, but then there’s a trailer for Fifty Shades before every single movie - even art movies, indy comedies, no matter the demographic. Next commandment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Straight boys, thou shalt have sex with your bros.
It’s obvious you love each other. You know that one guy, you know the one… and you know what? It doesn’t make you gay to fuck him. Brokeback Mountain was made by an all straight cast, writers and director; you don’t have to be gay in order to claim gay shit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I mean, it would be so hot if you two would just fuck. Give AND receive at least once in your life or you’ll plateau. But I mean take all this with a grain of salt because a word of caution - both Rebenca and I have a fatal flaw where we are queer and think everyone else is queer deep down. And that’s just plain wrong. Yet, my errant notions are not what is currently causing god’s wrath: the sex misery currently clogging up social media is the problem. Rebenca is bothered. And you don’t want to know when she gets very bothered. She goes hard. Listen to Rebenca’s next commandment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thou shalt talk about what you like and dislike before, during and after sex.
Talking about what you’re into doesn’t ruin the moment. Know what you might want to do on your date and know what you absolutely will not do. What you want to do is not the same as what your date must do. Ask your date what they want. Tell them what you want. Rinse. Repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Even Fifty Shades gets that right probably. I haven’t seen any of the movies. None of us have. Just the trailers. Is it just queers, angels, demons and other supernatural creatures who can’t stand the Fifty Shades franchise? We haven’t truly considered that narrow-minded individuals might actually like Fifty Shades. It’s possible that Rebenca’s punishment may not be a punishment after all. It’s like when we ejected Adam and Eve from the garden: these things backfire on us sometimes. But I mean. Nah. Fifty Shades is literally a dull porno made by cutting clips from the sad parts of a pharmaceutical commercial. Yeah, it’s a decent enough punishment that should effect change. Yeah. OK! So final commandment. And this one - I think it sucks. If I’m being honest, this one is just Rebenca making some shit up and hoping it sticks. It’s kind of like two commandments… but it’s not even a commandment like technically. I’m just asking that you don’t shoot the messenger.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assault is not your fault and thou shalt not be nice.
When going on a date, try sporting a confident, devil-may-care attitude. For femmes, the threat of being potentially tacitly under threat of a crime that is only prosecuted 1% of the time, it can be hard to feel as freewheeling as the masculine types who may never have felt threatened. Try to get into the headspace that you don’t live in a society where 1 in 6 women are victims of rape and attempted rape. You’ll find it’s a fun escape from reality. I know that’s a lot of fictionalizing, but for those of you who are good at make-believing when you’re being gaslit: why not apply your superpower to your own sexual gratification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know I said, God, you are mean. Also maybe not so much stats. And then Rebenca was like, but they don’t believe in anything that isn’t evidence-based. So, she won that argument. Rebenca wins every argument, being the most usually drunk and stubborn being I have ever met. But at least she’s not a borderline criminal. Anyhow, I wanted to make this one more fun like it should be so let’s switch gears a lot now.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Guess what!? It’s time to play, ladeez! Turn the tables with a some silly lady shenanigans for once!? Amiright ladeez!? Play dress up by returning from the bathroom with a metal probe and actual shit in your hair. Your man will be attentive while pretending not to be weirded out. In other words, take control. Go gurl and other aphorisms popularized by Pinterest &amp;amp; Instagram and ruinously emblazoned on otherwise perfectly fine T-shirts at ROSS Dress for Less. You know what I’m talking about my biatches and bashes and beeshies my beastlettes!’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I realize I’m not very relatable; I’m an angel. I’m here to deliver these commandments, which, I told Rebenca, is so Old Testament in a world where even the New Testament is tired. The one new thing we have is ignorant and outdated. And most people don’t even believe in anything unless it’s in the form of a popular meme. And here I am delivering stone tablets made out of stone with writing that was chiseled into them with chisels. Google stores every last tidbit we do on the internet, but one good bulldozing and these laws are toast, I told Rebenca. I’ll just leave these here, at the reference desk at the Brooklyn Public Library. You can’t check them out, but you can look at them. Maybe check the Library’s twitter feed. It should be a big deal for them. Sheesh, let’s hope it is. In closing, change your non-consensual ways, while there’s still time. Melania is currently hard at work ghost writing the next Fifty Shades franchise, but it doesn’t have to be this way. It has been decreed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poster: For basic ladies who considered S&amp;amp;M when the Kirkland is enough.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Sex" /><category term="Conversation" /><summary type="html">“Hey there believers, it’s Angel Rafael here, with another vlog post. This time I’m in The Brooklyn Public Library. It’s the middle of the night. I was sent here to deliver these stone tablets with news from this one god named Rebenca. She’s the one who helps you get tax breaks out of the blue. And avoid meter maids. One time she made a meter maid trip and fall while he was ticketing a person who just lost their job. That Rebenca! She watches soaps and drinks whiskey sours all day. Then goes on walks through the galactic rainforest. Rebenca helped write three of the original commandments. Oh and she gives out EXTRA GOOD multiple orgasms to everyone, male or female, who is pure of heart. She throws parties every time the moons 3 galaxies away get full, which is most months. Oh Rebenca! Always wears these wild purple velvet gowns with three gemstones dangling on each shoulder pad. This week it’s rubies.’</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22holytabs.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry></feed>