<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-04T10:01:13-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Queer Auntie</title><subtitle>The blog of writer Regina Clarkinia</subtitle><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><entry><title type="html">Astro Extras Feb 1-19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/astrology/Astrology-Extra.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Astro Extras Feb 1-19" /><published>2019-02-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/astrology/Astrology-Extra</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/astrology/Astrology-Extra.html">&lt;h5&gt;the tattoo: an astro activity&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;here’s a little activity for this week. you will need a paper and pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;what is one way in which you are both mis-understood and ahead of your time? (awaken, teen angst)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;you hold the key to how things could be more fair for everyone. write it down in a 3-word manifesto.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;draw your personal ID symbol based on your 3-word manifesto.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;with ball-point pen, draw your symbol on your arm.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;this week, scavenge for another person’s manifesto, but don’t ask them outright. see if you can glean it. listen to their way, what is special about them, what makes them tick, their foods, customs and the way they show thanks. listen closely and with deeper sensitivity than ever. listen so close that you could play a drum solo of their heart and breath. be a guest at their table. notice how they do things in a way you would have never considered. draw and write your findings.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Extra planetary mumbo-jumbo for astro nerds&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standouts this month are Aquarius and its ruling planet, Uranus. Both the Sun and Mercury are in Aquarius through mid-February. Uranus is doing its victory lap in Aries before &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/astrology/uranus-enters-taurus&quot;&gt;going back into Taurus&lt;/a&gt; in March. Uranus has been firing up this new sense of identity over the last eight-ish years in Aries, aggressively powering through into a radical new design. We have lots of exciting aspects to Uranus coming up in the next couple weeks. The Venus trine is making it about relationships, tone, design, rhythm and finding a way to bring some connectivity and sweetness to the freakazoid new individual flare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with Uranus, Mars is also finishing its (much shorter) run in Aries. Mars kicked off the month with a square to Pluto and will be conjunct Mars on Feb 13, which promises to be off the hook weirdo energy, cumming like a pinball machine on another planet flashing TILT and like smoke is everywhere. At any rate, it should be a good day for online porn.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Astrology" /><category term="Activities" /><category term="Tattoo" /><category term="Uranus" /><category term="Transits" /><summary type="html">the tattoo: an astro activity here’s a little activity for this week. you will need a paper and pen.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22john_walter.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22John%20Walter!%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22www.them.us/story/john-walter-capsid%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Astrology Feb 1-19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/astrology/Help-Astrology.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Astrology Feb 1-19" /><published>2019-02-02T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/astrology/Help-Astrology</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/astrology/Help-Astrology.html">&lt;h5&gt;Ask for help. Offer help.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These next couple weeks will be increasingly high energy. You might surprise yourself at how much you will be able to accomplish. At the same time, it can be easy to get frenzied. It can help to have your out-of-this-world grand plans connected to a results-oriented project, practical daily routine or be in collaboration with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A visualization for this: ride a wave of electric inspiration. If you start to think you know everything or try to do too much, you will wipe out, dude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal identity is super activated right now. You see it in the hideous red MAGA caps, but also in how identity politics have more prevalence and it seems like asking for each other’s pronouns is becoming more mainstream. In the next couple of weeks, you’ll follow the urge to express and try new things from this newfound sense of self. It’s like getting a new bike and wanting to ride it everywhere you go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may feel like helping others, which can grow into an inspired sense of thinking you know what is right for everyone. As long as you keep it grounded, or, you know, maybe ask them what they want. The high ideals and wild-hair inspirations that hit like a flash of lightning are good when you are connected to reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of this year is going to have a lot to do with taking care of ourselves, taking care of others and letting others take care of us. We can be heard better than ever and we can listen better than ever. This year is excellent for creative projects, like art, music and poetry that help other people, express an altruistic message or just are deep in the feels. It’s a good time to follow your dreams and do the impossible. The recipe for success = patient regular work time + heart is in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can sound like I’m saying this year will be all peace and love and hippy dippy easy breezy, but you know that making art when you’re tuned in to others can be super emotionally taxing. It’s like walking a tightrope while cuddling a fuzzy wuzzy baby bear. In this kind of astro weather, it can be easy to hide away, take a pre-fab job, binge on media and just isolate. None of these things is wrong. I encourage the following of the heart, whatever that means to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Astrology" /><category term="Horoscope" /><summary type="html">Ask for help. Offer help.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22posters.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3Enil,%20%22creditlink%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">T-shirts and bread</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/education/Student-Help.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="T-shirts and bread" /><published>2019-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/education/Student-Help</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/education/Student-Help.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/education/rumi&quot;&gt;Teachers, families and students are fighting for public school education in Oakland, CA.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a way to help out, here are some easy things you can do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hellaheartteachers.com&quot;&gt;Buy a T-shirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceeds go to OEA’s membership assistance fund which gives strike hardship grants to teachers who are actively participating in a strike. More than shirts have been purchased already. Printed at Movement Ink, a shop in Oakland’s Laurel District. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hellaheartteachers.com&quot;&gt;They’re cute. They’re red. And you should get one.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/keeppublicschoolsopen-gmail-com-keep-our-neighborhood-public-schools-open-f805c663-e4b0-49d6-8837-bc1863c4a0ee?recruiter=44321053&amp;amp;utm&quot;&gt;Sign the petition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parents teachers students &amp;amp; community started this petition to show the OUSD board and Superintendent Dr. Kyla Johnson-Trammell that voters see what is happening and that we stand in solidarity with the students and their families. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/keeppublicschoolsopen-gmail-com-keep-our-neighborhood-public-schools-open-f805c663-e4b0-49d6-8837-bc1863c4a0ee?recruiter=44321053&amp;amp;utm&quot;&gt;The list is growing fast!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://donorbox.org/breadfored&quot;&gt;Give $10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://donorbox.org/breadfored&quot;&gt;Bread for Ed&lt;/a&gt; is a campaign to provide meals at solidarity schools, food trucks at picket lines. The vast majority of Oakland students depend on free or reduced lunches, so this food fund is a critical show of solidarity with the Oakland community. &lt;a href=&quot;https://donorbox.org/breadfored&quot;&gt;Give a delicious donation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/346319642764768/&quot;&gt;Follow Oakland High on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get updates on the latest about the strike and other ways you can get involved. If you like to post stories you’re passionate about on facebook, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/346319642764768/&quot;&gt;you can share these posts to let more people know about the students in Oakland.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Education" /><category term="Kids" /><category term="Help" /><category term="Oakland" /><summary type="html">Teachers, families and students are fighting for public school education in Oakland, CA.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22oakteegirl.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Wear%20your%20care%20with%20a%20t-shirt%20and%20hoodie.%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22www.hellaheartteachers.com%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New-ish</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/education/Rumi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New-ish" /><published>2019-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/education/Rumi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/education/Rumi.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rumikoshino.com/section/203890-Sculpture-Installation.html&quot;&gt;Rumi Koshino&lt;/a&gt; is an artist and teacher. For three years she has been teaching at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ousd.org/domain/1712&quot;&gt;Oakland High,&lt;/a&gt; where the teachers are probably going to strike this February. I called her a few nights ago and asked how she’s doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh my god. It’s crazy. Exhausting. It’s all messed up. I don’t know what’s going on. I’m hearing it’s not new. I’m learning all of this as a new-ish teacher.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never known her to be this excited, and I have known Rumi for years, first as a fan of &lt;a href=&quot;https://vignettes.us/rumi-koshino-red-and-blue/&quot;&gt;her art.&lt;/a&gt; And later as a collaborator and friend. She is calm, caring, steady and buoyant; she doesn’t dramatize things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/dt_banner.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumi feels lucky to be at Oakland High. She works in a big, bright classroom with large windows. Oakland High is on a “block schedule”, which means she gets to teach three long classes each day instead of, say, five short classes. Her colleagues “are focused on equity and social justice” and she said, “It’s rare to have such a good relationship between staff and teachers. The principal is African-American Muslim. He’s calm, grounded and available. He know’s what’s happening, he’s there for us. And the assistant principals work hard.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently living in San Francisco, Rumi has been on the west coast for over ten years, but she grew up in Japan, “where everyone was Japanese.” Rumi’s students are from every corner of the globe. She told me, “It’s such a privilege to have this diversity. My students are all kids of color. They come from Yemen, Central America, Guatemala, El Salvador, China, mixed races and Oakland kids who only know Oakland. I tell them, ‘You don’t even know how lucky you are! This is like the United Nations.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/oakhighart_snow.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her students run the gamut of typical teenaged emotions: awkward, passionate, engaged, annoying, funny, active, heartbroken, in-love, sensitive, brilliant, curious… Unlike kids at some other schools where Rumi previously worked, where students were “only 15-years-old and already learned to kiss the teacher’s ass for grades.” In comparison, she says, “Oakland kids, they’re so honest. They speak their mind and that allows me to be honest. To be myself.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumi is honest too: “If I didn’t like my school and my situation, I would teach in San Francisco and GET PAID.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oakland schools are experiencing a teacher retention crisis. The district is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eastbaytimes.com/2018/09/19/debt-ridden-oakland-unified-to-get-34-7-million-state-bailout/&quot;&gt;deeply in debt&lt;/a&gt; and teachers have been without a contract for the past year. In negotiation with the Oakland Unified School District (OUSD), teachers are asking for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Smaller class sizes and lower Special Education case loads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More student support, like librarians, counselors, psychologists and restorative justice coordinators&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A living wage (12% raise)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/dt_photographer.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for how this can be paid for, Rumi said,“The OUSD admin give themselves a lot of money but then they say there is a budget crisis. They could solve the crisis if they cut their salaries. They spend a huge amount of money on consultancies. And a lot of the money goes to lawyers to cover their own backs. But teachers get lower than a living wage and can’t afford to live in Oakland. There is a teacher retention crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All January, Oakland teachers have been mobilizing. Rumi explained, “It’s energizing and exhausting at the same time. We teach all day, and after we go to meetings about strikes and the school board meetings. It’s like going to night school. I’m learning all these new things, like how it works and how it’s totally messed up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/oakhighart_night.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that is “totally messed up” is the OUSD’s threat to close 1/3 of its non-charter public schools. Last year, the OUSD board passed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oaklandpost.org/2018/11/30/oakland-unified-moves-forward-plan-close-24-schools/&quot;&gt;“The Community of Schools Policy,”&lt;/a&gt; which will close as many as 24 public schools in the next 5 years. Luckily, Rumi’s school, Oakland High, is not on that list. However, all of the schools slated to be closed are in East Oakland and West Oakland, serving poc and low-income communities. All schools located in the hills, that serve financially stable communities, and that have more white students, are safe from the shut-down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The charter school industry has been working on Oakland as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/education/school-crisis&quot;&gt;“portfolio district”&lt;/a&gt; for over 20 years. The OUSD Board has been collaborating with the charter school lobby. Starting with the poorest neighborhoods, they destabilize existing public schools, force school shut-downs and replace them with charter schools. The objective of the “portfolio district” blueprint is to privatize education by converting public schools into investment portfolio products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meetings Rumi has been going to have been a crash course in this fraught history; it’s like OUSD 101. She says, “It’s a lot! But we’re doing it for our work and our students. I see the school children coming together and speaking up for themselves: it’s energizing and empowering to see.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/roots_megaphone.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 23, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eastbaytimes.com/2019/01/28/roots-middle-school-to-close/&quot;&gt;the OUSD board voted to close ROOTS International Academy in East Oakland.&lt;/a&gt; Rumi said, “The students, parents and teachers spoke at the OUSD board meeting. &lt;a href=&quot;http://ousd.granicus.com/mediaplayer.php?clip_id=1401&quot;&gt;They are so good at articulating what they want with the facts to back it up.&lt;/a&gt; I would hope to be able to speak with such heartfelt passion to really move people!” However, the board sat stone-face, showing no signs of interest or concern. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kqed.org/news/11716967/oaklands-school-closure-plans-off-to-a-rough-start-for-some-parents&quot;&gt;It is hard to keep going when the school board makes big decisions without showing any consideration for community input.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumi shifts between feeling inspired, resilient and at times defeated. She told me, “Negotiation. Communication. Those words! I feel like it’s not working. Who are the board getting money from? Our school board member, Aimee Eng, gave us the run around.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/roots_grampa.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After the ROOTS vote it just felt hopeless. All the schools they close are in underserved neighborhoods. Like ROOTS is at International and 60th in East Oakland. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rootsinternationalacademy.com/we-know-where-we-come-from&quot;&gt;ROOTS is really thriving!&lt;/a&gt; Small schools like ROOTS are important to the neighborhood. Now kids have to walk 35 blocks to get to class. It’s very unsafe, a human trafficking hub. Kids are afraid to be on the street. All except one member on the OUSD board voted to close the school.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/dt_baby.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s impossible to not feel distracted by the the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postnewsgroup.com/2019/01/22/parents-ask-whos-behind-roots-school-closure/&quot;&gt;apparent corruption&lt;/a&gt; behind the board’s baffling decisions. The OUSD administration and the charter school lobby have leveraged hard to peddle this idea that keeping schools open creates financial loss, when in fact enrollment funding is their prime source of revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past year and a half, Rumi and her colleagues have been in the process of negotiating with the OUSD through their union rep. It is a process of voting, sending the vote to the district, waiting and voting again. Rumi just sent me an email saying, “Our strike vote will be counted tomorrow. I’ll let you know what the result will be as soon as I find out!” Tomorrow is Saturday, February 2, 2019. I will update this article when I hear back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/oakhighart_barber.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Education" /><category term="Kids" /><category term="poc" /><category term="Artist" /><category term="Teacher" /><category term="Oakland" /><category term="Schools" /><category term="Art" /><summary type="html">Rumi Koshino is an artist and teacher. For three years she has been teaching at Oakland High, where the teachers are probably going to strike this February. I called her a few nights ago and asked how she’s doing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22rumi_header.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3Enil,%20%22creditlink%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">California Public School Crisis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/education/School-Crisis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="California Public School Crisis" /><published>2019-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/education/School-Crisis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/education/School-Crisis.html">&lt;h5&gt;The basic blueprint&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against all odds, students in California’s poorest neighborhoods shine brightly in public schools, but when lobby-controlled school boards close their schools, they are forced to fight for an education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should be a story about these students, their teachers and families. &lt;a href=&quot;http://ousd.granicus.com/player/clip/1401?fbclid=IwAR0jkimaNOdAAqyba3GYzQrJYGgMIqnIqssfzu0IFFu_PHRmk42x231Lntg&quot;&gt;They are speaking out&lt;/a&gt; and doing everything they can to keep their schools open. But the students have no leverage: they don’t have a lot of money and they are not white. &lt;a href=&quot;https://edsource.org/2019/oakland-school-board-votes-to-close-first-of-up-to-two-dozen-schools-amid-opposition/607844?fbclid=IwAR1Qh3UT6rI245V4JHOvyjOGHhHuTe88Hxrsn4mH5nUBXc8_2xMD8hcX_tM&quot;&gt;So the school board ignores them.&lt;/a&gt; And regular citizens don’t hear the students either. They don’t feel the urgency, even though it’s their own hard-earned taxpayer money getting funneled into &lt;a href=&quot;https://beyondtradeoffs.economist.com/implementing-billion-dollar-mandate&quot;&gt;private investment portfolios.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rootsinternationalacademy.com/we-know-where-we-come-from&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/roots_pictures.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Students from ROOTS International Academy&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could say, “Imagine it’s your kid that suddenly has to find a new school.” or “These kids are just like you were when you were in high school. They just want experiences, opportunities, relationships and a safe place to be teenagers.“ and then I’d say, “Remember when you were in high school?” and then you’d say, “I’d rather not.” Which is understandable. For those of us who had the privilege of school, it is was a dreaded delight to really just hate it to death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oaklandpost.org/2018/12/27/school-district-wants-close-roots-international-academy-school-year/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/roots_field.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this doesn’t really have anything to do with these students, as much as it cuts to admit this. Thanks to racism, classism and political shell games, this isn’t about the students, the awkward geniuses, who usually but not always bloom where they’re planted. It should be about them because they are the real protagonists, the heroes of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story is a showdown between the charter school lobbyists and the teacher’s unions. The charter school lobby has been systematically taking over public schools in California for over two decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works. In order to convert public schools into investment packages, the charter school industry targets a vulnerable region, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://greatlakescenter.org/docs/Policy\_Briefs/Saltman\_PortfolioDistricts.pdf&quot;&gt;a “portfolio district”,&lt;/a&gt; where they gain political influence over the school board. Starting with the poorest neighborhoods, they destabilize existing public schools, force school shut-downs, install charter schools and deliver financial returns to investors. That’s the basic blueprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;The “portfolio district” blueprint being played out in Oakland&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oakland Unified School District board members receive massive campaign funds from both &lt;a href=&quot;https://edsource.org/2018/charter-school-supporters-and-critics-are-big-spenders-in-some-bay-area-school-board-elections/604403&quot;&gt;the teacher unions and the charter school lobby.&lt;/a&gt; Basically, the unions want teachers to get paid and the lobby wants to convert public schools into investment packages. The charters disproportionately target neighborhoods where students have to contend with living in high-stress, violent environments with everyday threats like child trafficking and homelessness.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oaklandpost.org/2018/11/30/oakland-unified-moves-forward-plan-close-24-schools/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/ousd.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oaklandpost.org/2018/11/30/oakland-unified-moves-forward-plan-close-24-schools/&quot;&gt;On June 27th, 2018, the OUSD board passed “The Community of Schools Policy,”&lt;/a&gt; which will close as many as 24 public schools in the next 5 years. All closures affect East Oakland and West Oakland schools that serve poc and low-income communities, in the area known as the “flatlands”. All schools located in the hills, that serve financially stable communities and that have more white students are safe from the shut-down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://edsource.org/2019/oakland-school-board-votes-to-close-first-of-up-to-two-dozen-schools-amid-opposition/607844?fbclid=IwAR1Qh3UT6rI245V4JHOvyjOGHhHuTe88Hxrsn4mH5nUBXc8_2xMD8hcX_tM&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/flatlands.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deciding factor in school closures seems to be the neighborhood’s lack of financial and political leverage. It has nothing to do with the quality of the school. Even good schools get shut down with no consideration for the school’s deeply ingrained, positive impact on the community. For example, this month (January 2019) the OUSD board voted to close ROOTS International Academy, a thriving school in East Oakland. The board was unmoved by &lt;a href=&quot;https://edsource.org/2019/oakland-school-board-votes-to-close-first-of-up-to-two-dozen-schools-amid-opposition/607844?fbclid=IwAR1Qh3UT6rI245V4JHOvyjOGHhHuTe88Hxrsn4mH5nUBXc8_2xMD8hcX_tM&quot;&gt;the outpouring of heartfelt support&lt;/a&gt; from family, teachers and students at the OUSD board meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oaklandxings.com/category/charter-schools-and-privatization/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/roots_speaker.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Direct accounting vs the runaround&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OUSD runs $30 million over budget. The reasons for this shortfall include loss of revenue to charter schools, mismanagement by the OUSD administration and borrowing hundreds of millions from the state that they struggle to pay back. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oaklandpost.org/2018/09/14/ousd-may-receive-millions-state-aid-money-comes-strings/&quot;&gt;The Alameda County Office of Education and the Fiscal Crisis and Management Assistance Team (FCMAT) have swooped in many times,&lt;/a&gt; advising the OUSD to shut down more schools, lay off more teachers and take out state loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, research has shown that closing schools and laying off faculty loses money by cutting off the primary source of revenue, student enrollment funds. It is also well-documented that shutting down replacing public schools with charters almost always costs more. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nepc.colorado.edu/publication/closures&quot;&gt;a recent UC Berkeley study&lt;/a&gt; states that is “a  high-risk/low-gain strategy that fails to hold promise with respect to either student achievement or non-cognitive well-being.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teachers, parents and community advocates are asking for more practical steps to reaching solvency: their solutions all amount to more transparency. And right now is the time to make this happen. The California Legislature recently passed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eastbaytimes.com/2018/09/19/debt-ridden-oakland-unified-to-get-34-7-million-state-bailout/&quot;&gt;Education Trailer Bill, which offers the OUSD district a grant of $34.7 million&lt;/a&gt; to be doled out over the next three years, but they can only receive this funding if they cut $30 million in their annual budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public school advocates want to balance the budget by going to the source of the problem, basic accounting. Proposed solutions include hiring a Chief Financial Officer to establish financial accountability, to shine a light on how funds are being mismanaged and to create a strategy to reduce expensive consultancies and bloated admin salaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kqed.org/news/11716967/oaklands-school-closure-plans-off-to-a-rough-start-for-some-parents&quot;&gt;Parents were dumbfounded by the sudden push to close ROOTS International Academy.&lt;/a&gt; They found out via a robocall in December 2018 and less than a month later, the board voted to shut down their kids’ school. The OUSD continues to willfully lose student enrollment funds by closing schools, while making the claim that it is to “save money”. This sounds like gas lighting, the parasitic kryptonite that leeches off of earnest endeavors. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postnewsgroup.com/2019/01/22/parents-ask-whos-behind-roots-school-closure/&quot;&gt;Parents just want to know what’s really going on.&lt;/a&gt; They want to know if the board and other public organizations are being influenced by the charter school lobby, including GO Pub­lic School, Educate78, New Schools Venture Fund and the California Charter School As­sociation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;The difference between individual charter schools and the charter school industry&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charter schools have devoted supporters. And every charter school is unique. I used to work at two excellent charter schools in the Bay Area. Many students, teachers and parents have found charters to provide a unique home for academic success. Parents who are frustrated with public schools should have the option to move their kids to a school that offers what they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like regular public schools, charter schools are tuition-free public schools that receive public funds based on enrollment and attendance. The only difference is in the charter, or contract, that spells out the way they operate based on a unique vision and alternative approach to educational success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that the financial industry found a way to prey on this unique arrangement. The private charter industry pays off school board members in their hunt for student enrollment money. When this happens, the school board board no longer acts as an impartial servant for student academic success. The board becomes a puppet for a strategic takeover by increasing school closures without consideration for its traumatizing impact on underserved and poc children. The objective of the “district portfolio” blueprint is to privatize education by converting all public schools into investment portfolio products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.financial-planning.com/list/aibnb-charter-schools-unusual-real-estate-strategies&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/cash.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The charter school lobby argues that public schools have gotten complacent and don’t provide a good education. Their thinking supports privatization of public services in general: open market competition “naturally” breeds excellence and provides consumers with more options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teacher’s unions claim that the effects of charter school industry strategies, such as destabilizing existing public schools and selectively recruiting high performing students, are a drain on enrollment dollars and this financial blow drastically cuts into resources for underserved and poc public school students. The teacher’s unions want a moratorium on the creation of new charter schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;A temporary moratorium on the &quot;portfolio district&quot; blueprint in Los Angeles&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, on January 29, &lt;a href=&quot;https://laist.com/2019/01/29/lausd_board_asks_state_to_temporarily_halt_new_charter_schools_from_opening.php&quot;&gt;the LAUSD board declared a temporary hiatus on the formation of new charter schools&lt;/a&gt; in order to take a step back and analyze charter school impact. A comprehensive study by the California Department of Education is expected to be published late 2019 and will examine the more than two decades of charter school growth in California, the state with the most charter schools in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://edsource.org/2019/la-unified-teachers-still-face-challenges-over-contract-and-charter-school-moratorium/607910&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/lausdboard.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://edsource.org/2019/la-unified-teachers-still-face-challenges-over-contract-and-charter-school-moratorium/607910&quot;&gt;The LAUSD board doesn’t actually have the power to suspend new charter schools;&lt;/a&gt; this is something the California Legislature would likely have to approve. The LAUSD board’s action is more of a “please help us” signal to Sacramento, where a statewide cap on charter schools has been talked about. The OUSD board piggy-backed on to the LAUSD’s plea, letting Sacramento know that they want to be included in a statewide cap, if it happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newly elected State Superintendent of Public Instruction, Tony Thurmond, &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/11/01/california-superintendent-of-public-instruction-charter-schools/&quot;&gt;has promised a pause on charter school expansion.&lt;/a&gt; Governor Gavin Newsom is more vague, supporting investigations into conflicts of interest and more transparency in the charter school industry, however he hasn’t spoken out about a moratorium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/tony.thurmond/photos/a.288388564670642/1173743649468458/?type=1&amp;amp;theater&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/assets/img/thurmond.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the OUSD board, most of the LAUSD board members have received large payments from the charter lobby, so this “temporary moratorium” on new charters may be a way to appear temporarily unbiased. The charter school lobby has proven to be excellent at their long game, finding ways to diffuse any obvious correlation between the lobby’s campaign donations and pro-charter bias on school boards across California.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="California" /><category term="Education" /><category term="Kids" /><category term="poc" /><summary type="html">The basic blueprint</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22crunching_numbers.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3Enil,%20%22creditlink%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Uranus Enters Taurus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/astrology/Uranus-Enters-Taurus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uranus Enters Taurus" /><published>2018-05-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/astrology/Uranus-Enters-Taurus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/astrology/Uranus-Enters-Taurus.html">&lt;p&gt;Uranus moves through signs very slowly, in each sign for like 7 or more years… so I like to see how this unfolds. Even though the fateful day of the transition is meaningful and it’s funny you actually can notice the switch, I like to wait and see what we foment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a metaphor: planet transiting through a sign like making sauerkraut. At the beginning of a transit it’s like when you first put cabbage and salt covered up - no real change yet. It’s a big change in the sense that cabbage that was once whole is now chopped into a thousand tiny pieces, but there’s no fermentation developing yet. Day one, two, three, four… try not to peek because not much has changed. One week in, not ready to eat but change, yes, Taste, you can feel where it’s going with this but it hasn’t peaked. Whats in the air makes a difference in the flavor. Then 2 weeks or more in is a good time, yes, we see what has developed and how this particular transit has affected things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For contrast to Uranus in each sign for 7 years, the moon is perhaps the fastest mover of the “planets”… in each sign for like two and a half days. You can really feel that change since it starts-&amp;gt;middle-&amp;gt;ends so quickly, and it strikes at the gut and emotions. Quick pickle… or scratch that: fast fermentation. The moon is subconscious, vibesy, feelings, moods, hidden or invisible tendrils… to define as examples of how you can perceive moon stuff, just for the sake of noticing in our world, in others and self how the Moon dyes daily life things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another comparison, the Sun is in each sign for a month. It’s very conscious, logical and the ways we openly express. and conspicuously espouse ideas and actions. Like when people say, “I’ve been very busy on lots of projects. My calendar is very full.” What they brag and/or humble-brag about is where you see the Sun doing it’s magic. You can also see the sun’s influence in holidays - open celebrations that the whole culture gets behind. Or like bumper sticker saying it plain: My Kid is an Honor Roll Student. Whereas with the moon - they’ll express through a mood. If you want to catch their drift, you have to pick up on facial expressions, subtle glances, thickness and quality of the air, a lilt of their walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Uranus - it’s electrified, weird, unemotional and altruistic, with a bee in the bonnet to erect new-fangled public works projects to bring everyone into the future, more equality, integrity… like a shot in the arm. I always think of the mad scientist from Back to the Future. In Taurus, the first thing I think is prolific growth, sprouting new weird creative social projects, totally new ways of valuing work, new architecture for the financial system, innovations on farming and feeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uranus is currently opposite Jupiter which is like limited bleak outlook, and combative resentful bucking at this. (the way to have backbone in this scenario is hope. It’s a choice, to some degree - whats in the air affects the fermentation.) But in 7 years by the time Uranus is ready to complete the time in Taurus, Jupiter will have just uplifted and filled Uranus in Taurus with it’s big fatty luck charms. Whatever we’ve built will get bigger - greed or hope or equality or whatever we want to make. Also in 7 years, Saturn will be in Pisces and Neptune will be in Aries… all of which points to renovation and new chances for how society, the masses, large groups interact, feedback, connect and bounce off each other to weave our oceanic constellation fabric. We have a lot of say on how this turns out. Uranus in Taurus for 7 or something years… what will that ferment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uranus has been in Aries for 7 years. What did we get from that? Maybe all these new civil rights and more mainstream awareness of terrorism against poc, queer, women, etc… since Aries is a combative avenger that hates lies and instinctively kicks towards what feels true for family/brothers/sisters/lovers. I don’t know. Whatever it is, we will make it and it will be ours. Do you have any ideas?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Uranus" /><category term="Transits" /><category term="Astrology" /><summary type="html">Uranus moves through signs very slowly, in each sign for like 7 or more years… so I like to see how this unfolds. Even though the fateful day of the transition is meaningful and it’s funny you actually can notice the switch, I like to wait and see what we foment.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22kraut.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Creative%20Commons/%20Flickr%20Sarah%20Warren%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22https://flic.kr/p/d2iAQb%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Museum at F.I.T.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/museum/The-Museum-at-FIT.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Museum at F.I.T." /><published>2018-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/museum/The-Museum-at-FIT</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/museum/The-Museum-at-FIT.html">&lt;p&gt;Late April. Around 5:30pm. I’m walking down the street to a see a museum show about high fashion for different body types. Right out in public, in the middle of busy Manhattan, a class of bootcampers side-shuffle from one side of the one-lane street to the other. At any moment, a car could drive through them, or want to drive through them. The instructor shouts commands in a heavy New York accent. I imagined he had been a fire fighter or a cop who survived 9-11 and couldn’t work the job anymore due to PTSD. He decided on a career change: to use his aggressive tenacity to motivate 20-somethings into shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest slackers, a tall beefy gay man and two straight women, entertained each other in muffled comments and exaggerated reactions to the drills, theatrically expressing how tired they were. Most everyone wore yoga style sleeveless T-shirts (the kind that hang like the top of a toga). The bootcamp’s motto was printed on the shirts, something like, “This ain’t no joke”. A good reminder that physical fitness is a matter of life or death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a bench on the promenade outside the Fashion Institute for Technology, to join the other gawkers. Lounging on benches in the mellow sun, about fifty of us stared expressionlessly at the bootcamp spectacle. One guy even had his camera up. It was quality footage for a 10-second snap, gram, tweet or meme-thing, just because of how bold it was to face the humiliation of constant onlookers. After the class did a bunch of squats in the only section of the street not parked in, the instructor indicated that it was now time to jog. They ran off in a line like ducklings, the slackers at the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed them down the block, into the fancy glass-walled lobby of The Museum at FIT. An indoors red carpet leads to the entrance of the museum, but for some reason it was cordoned off with movie theater velvet ropes. I went to walk around. A security guard sitting at a podium on my right suddenly asked me what I wanted and I said to see the museum. Security guards and doormen exist in every New York lobby. But they don’t necessarily greet you. They wait to see what you do. They are there to test peoples’ certitude. Are you in the right place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum is one long room, shaped like the letter L. If it was a golf course it would be called a dog leg, dimly lit. Clothing is displayed on dressing forms on a platform that runs along the walls on either side. You walk down the center, with clothing displays to your right and left. It’s like you’re on a catwalk and the fashions are looking at you! Several of us were smartly dressed. A businesslike woman wore red stockings, a pair of ladies had hats and me with the weird side burns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The red stockings woman spent a lot of time with each piece of clothing, probably reading every single placard, like I did, and always have since I could read and go to museums. Isn’t Delmonico’s a thing? I would like to go there with this 60-year-old woman and have a steak and wine and talk about the weather and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eavesdropped on the hat-wearing pair of women. One listened. The other spoke in Spanglish. Quick to judge. Theatrically editorializing on the Donna Karan shoulder pads dress. Loves Donna Karan. Owns a DK couture thing which makes her say the name, Donna Karan, with familiarity. Spoke disparagingly of Rei Kawakubo, which even though RK is my favorite, I totally get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kawakubo Dress. This dress is from the 1980s show called “Body Meet Dress. Dress Meet Body.” Form-fitting. Stretchy material. With lumps of stuffing here and there in unexpected places like the hip or arm or anywhere. If one can have shoulder pads or a bustle on the butt, then why not enhancements in other places. Reminds me of Bouffon outfits, which makes sense because Kawakubo is often mocking the ignorance of fashion norms and ridiculous standards for what a female body is supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were so many guards, it felt like overkill. But then, it’s in the middle of Manhattan where a zillion people are doing whatever they want everywhere. You never know who might walk, jog or side-shuffle in. The guards, noticeably gentlemanly and wonderfully adept at containing being stir-crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not far from the Kawakubo dress is a package of Spanx. Across from the Kawakubo dress, an actual bustle is on display. Posterior is the word for butt here. There are also different variations on corsets and girdles on display, including a pregnant woman’s corset and a little girl corset. There was also a pregnant woman’s isolation cloak, for when women were meant to quarantine themselves during their unsightly pregnancies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dress from the 1960s with plastic windows down the sides reveals the body, and the show description infers that the woman wouldn’t wear anything underneath a dress like this. The dress had the Courreges futuristic antiseptic but playful stiffness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clothing designs had to do with women covering up their bodies, until the 1960s when clothes revealed parts of the body in cheeky places. When fashion required women to show more skin, exercise replaced bustles and corsets as the method of forming the body. The Museum at FIT has a video looping Olivia Newton-John’s “Let’s Get Physical” as well as a workout video from the 1980s blared upbeat music and instructions while women in pastel leotards and leg warmers followed along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens when you don’t wear the bras, spanks or work out obsessively? One of my favorite runway photos of all time is Liza Minelli at like 2014 Oscars wearing a bright blue limpid silk Halston pantsuit with no bra. It was very unpopular with the press. But Tumblr loved it and so did I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Mary looking for a place to give birth to Jesus Christ, Leslie Jones could not find a designer for the Ghostbusters premiere in 2016. Jones tweeted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s so funny how there are no designers wanting to help me with a premiere dress for movie. Hmmm that will change and I remember everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until Christian Soriano leapt at the chance to have Leslie Jones as a client. He designed a beautiful red dress, now on display the The FIT Museum. When people applauded his choice, Siriano tweeted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It shouldn’t be exceptional to work with brilliant people just because they’re not sample size. Congrats aren’t in order, a change is.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Museum" /><category term="Body Image" /><category term="Fashion" /><category term="Femme" /><summary type="html">Late April. Around 5:30pm. I’m walking down the street to a see a museum show about high fashion for different body types. Right out in public, in the middle of busy Manhattan, a class of bootcampers side-shuffle from one side of the one-lane street to the other. At any moment, a car could drive through them, or want to drive through them. The instructor shouts commands in a heavy New York accent. I imagined he had been a fire fighter or a cop who survived 9-11 and couldn’t work the job anymore due to PTSD. He decided on a career change: to use his aggressive tenacity to motivate 20-somethings into shape.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22physical.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Olivia%20Newton-John/%20Physical%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6zwPVU92-XQ%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sugar Hill Museum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/museum/Sugar-Hill-Museum.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sugar Hill Museum" /><published>2018-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/museum/Sugar-Hill-Museum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/museum/Sugar-Hill-Museum.html">&lt;p&gt;The Sugar Hill Museum, in the Sugar Hill neighborhood of Harlem, is full of interactive materials. Raw wood sticks with frayed bark in a horizontal built-in shelf, some just lying there, others in a natural fiber basket. They seem like props for kids to generate stories and I wondered how it worked. Same with the living room-sized chess board on the floor with toddler-sized chess pieces in the central open gallery space. Keeping track of any chess game would result in a story structure, since it has relationship, motivation, strategy to pull that off with devastating losses and smug victories, and every emotion in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There weren’t kids using the space when I was there, but The Sugar Hill Museum is a place for groups of kids to move, play, roll up their sleeves and activate their voices. I arrived at the front door wet from a misty rain and my own sweat. The eye liner from my eyes had drooped down to below my eyes, like a 1980s football quarterback, but I didn’t know this yet. The guy at the front was very friendly and we talked about the woes of gentrification and lots of other choir preaching tidbits. They weren’t usually open on Wednesday, so the galleries were pretty empty. It was just me an a security guard and I had to be let in to one of the galleries that was still locked. That’s how dead it was. But I could hear their screams and running feet. That’s how lucky I felt to be avoiding noisy kid mobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You enter the museum by walking down blonde wood stairs that lead to a central gallery, a high-ceilinged, open, versatile space, with that barn-sized chess game in the middle. To the right of the entrance, built-in risers offer audience seating in seven giant wood stairs. A show of mural-sized pieces designed by two of the curatorial staff cover the walls. The graphic design prints showcase blown-up historical photos of Sugar Hill residents in action, connecting and making things together. Each photo mirrors itself to create a kaleidoscope look, that gives the impression that people who share their stories accordion their worlds outward to supply the rest of the neighborhood with energy to grow together from within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This central gallery leads to two main galleries, and on the opposite side is a sloping corridor. One wall of the corridor is those sticks are that I was talking about. The other side of the corridor is a glass facade that opens into separate studio labs for kids and one artist-in-residence studio, which is bursting with flowing black ink on different white surfaces, from drawings on crumpled papers to a flat drawing of of a kid slumped over a swing, belly-down, like a rag on a kitchen sink spigot, you know how you used to do. The kids studios are full of inviting stations made for kids to tell their story in their own way, like if NPR’s recording studios were actual playgrounds. The stations seem to beckon the children, “Come hither and try to break me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two different shows in the main galleries. One is a room dedicated to Ana Mendieta’s projects with children. It was just the security guard and me, trying to be polite and friendly one another. I am a fan of Ana Mendieta, a Cuban American performance artist whose life was tragically cut short, allegedly murdered by her husband, allegedly also an artist. But this is about Ana Mendieta’s art and the way that she worked with children in a way that avoided leading questions and gave them the keys to the creative car. On the left side, a black and white wide-shot video she took of a class-size group of elementary school students playing together, with a full-size parachute, you know the game. Along the right and back walls, hung low to ground, kid-height, are photos of Mendieta with an abundance of facial hair glued to her face to create a Mario/Luigi-style mustache. In the back left corner is a listening nook, with a stool, two speakers and thoughtful and joyous kids voices talking about what they believe a soul to be in terms of time. The voices rev up then slow down like a car changing gears unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum’s description on the wall of the Ana Mendieta show says: “In this exhibition children are encouraged to reflect on notions of power and freedom through verbal and physical exploration.” This is the repeated theme throughout the museum and it got me thinking about how exploring thoughts and critical expression through physical activity, thinking in your body, and in a shared space, may be the best and only way to “reflect on notions of power and freedom”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the museum, the idea of producing a story isn’t confronted directly. Kids are courted into choosing to invent stories by accident, as a by-product of play. The show that is up in the other space takes the taboo of forcing kids to write, learn and produce, and instead of avoiding it, this show amplifies the tension to a game based on a new folkloric character. The Bibliobandido shows up in town once a month and extracts stories from the children. He’s like the Tooth Fairy, but with a spooky, mysterious, menacing, even threatening quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bibliobandido was co-created in a town in Honduras that artist, Marisa Jahn, was asked to help design a creative program to help increase child literacy. Before you go in, you take a battery-operated candle and you watch a video with kids from Honduras who have to contend with the Bibliobandido. They tell the stories that they have given to the Bibliobandido, whose gaunt, stylish roll, loping in on a horse, wearing a hat that covers their eyes and a poncho that covers their body. The Bibliobandido can be a woman one month, a man or a gender-fluid person the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The room is painted from floor to ceiling. Kids can write their own stories to save their lives on a short, kid-size table in the center of the room. When you leave the room, you tell your story through a hole in the wall, then hand over your candle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Time passing and change are undeniable aspects of the world around us…Often artistic creation results in the production of art objects. However, when a concern for time is primary, an experience not an object may result.” -Ana Mendieta&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Ana Mendieta quote, included on the wall of the show, speaks to how playing doesn’t always yield a physical object, other than the experience itself. And got me to thinking about the difference between creating work to be consumed versus the act of creative expression. Writing a script versus the moment of performing it. Having a gorgeous latte without sharing it on Instagram. Reminds me of doing “devised work”, a physical theater piece that is created collaboratively, “on its feet” rather than written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sugar Hill Museum facilitates play that doesn’t worry about yielding an object, such as a good story. I know how hard it can be to tell a story, especially when I want it to be good, or if I’m worried if people will like it, or if I feel like I don’t want to because I only want to tell stories on accident as a result of being with people, goofing off having fun. I love to generate new work, but the thing I fear is making it make sense with a clear statement, sharing it in the world and then being ridiculed. But if it’s do or die, as in the beautiful Bibliobandido will terrorize my family unless I speak a story through a make-believe conduit in some dry wall, then I will get the shit done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Be intent on action,&lt;br /&gt;
not on the fruits of action;&lt;br /&gt;
avoid attraction to the fruits&lt;br /&gt;
and attachment to inaction!”&lt;br /&gt;
— Bhagavad Gita, Translated by Barbara Stoler Miller&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Museum" /><category term="Storytelling" /><category term="Kids" /><category term="Education" /><summary type="html">The Sugar Hill Museum, in the Sugar Hill neighborhood of Harlem, is full of interactive materials. Raw wood sticks with frayed bark in a horizontal built-in shelf, some just lying there, others in a natural fiber basket. They seem like props for kids to generate stories and I wondered how it worked. Same with the living room-sized chess board on the floor with toddler-sized chess pieces in the central open gallery space. Keeping track of any chess game would result in a story structure, since it has relationship, motivation, strategy to pull that off with devastating losses and smug victories, and every emotion in the book.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22mendieta.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Ana%20Mendieta/%20Untitled%20(Facial%20Hair%20Transplants),%201972.%20%C2%A9%20The%20Estate%20of%20Ana%20Mendieta%20Collection,%20LLC.%20Courtesy%20Galerie%20Lelong%20&amp;%20Co.%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22http://www.galerielelong.com/%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Town Cats</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/poetry/Town-Cats.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Town Cats" /><published>2018-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/poetry/Town-Cats</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/poetry/Town-Cats.html">&lt;p&gt;Town Cats who &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; to own the turf.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s a jukebox of kittens.&lt;br /&gt;
They pee on the mats. Perfume!&lt;br /&gt;
Now that’s the ticket.&lt;br /&gt;
They &lt;strong&gt;start&lt;/strong&gt; to fight the House Cat.&lt;br /&gt;
The big owner invades!&lt;br /&gt;
They pee and have sex. Feline Infection!&lt;br /&gt;
They &lt;strong&gt;realize&lt;/strong&gt; they don’t mind the cars, that much anyways.&lt;br /&gt;
If they &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt; only &lt;strong&gt;get&lt;/strong&gt; Tommy to &lt;strong&gt;stop trying&lt;/strong&gt; an insurrection.&lt;br /&gt;
Bass drum. High hat. Scratch. Crash! Ride.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Poetry" /><category term="Music" /><category term="Cats" /><summary type="html">Town Cats who want to own the turf. It’s a jukebox of kittens. They pee on the mats. Perfume! Now that’s the ticket. They start to fight the House Cat. The big owner invades! They pee and have sex. Feline Infection! They realize they don’t mind the cars, that much anyways. If they can only get Tommy to stop trying an insurrection. Bass drum. High hat. Scratch. Crash! Ride.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22towncats.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Creative%20Commons/%20%E7%81%B0%E7%81%B0%E5%A6%88%20Wei%20Wei%20Ma%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22http://blog.sina.com.cn/xy541107%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">When It’s Just Dark</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/poetry/When-It-s-Just-Dark.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When It’s Just Dark" /><published>2018-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/poetry/When-It%E2%80%99s-Just-Dark</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/poetry/When-It-s-Just-Dark.html">&lt;p&gt;Sheets of hot tin roof go “waeahwaehhhweeaahhh,” a shimmering saw. Fleet-footed. A piece of cake pulled from the one cooling in the windah. Crumblings onto the unlit grass shards. Running through backyards in just the 1950s just a boy with a slingshot in yer pocket sayin’ “gee whiz” the neck snaps back, trachea bent into a dent by a cotton cord not always strung with clothes usually but not always. His birthright chances scatter like cat-eyes, surround where his spine lies. Their glassy flecks currying God-given favors, oven lives, clotheslines, boy oh boy cake freaks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Regina Clarkinia</name></author><category term="Poetry" /><category term="Noir" /><category term="Olden Days" /><category term="Boyhood" /><summary type="html">Sheets of hot tin roof go “waeahwaehhhweeaahhh,” a shimmering saw. Fleet-footed. A piece of cake pulled from the one cooling in the windah. Crumblings onto the unlit grass shards. Running through backyards in just the 1950s just a boy with a slingshot in yer pocket sayin’ “gee whiz” the neck snaps back, trachea bent into a dent by a cotton cord not always strung with clothes usually but not always. His birthright chances scatter like cat-eyes, surround where his spine lies. Their glassy flecks currying God-given favors, oven lives, clotheslines, boy oh boy cake freaks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22clothesline.jpg%22,%20%22teaser%22=%3Enil,%20%22credit%22=%3E%22Creative%20Commons/%20Flickr%20Mike%20Bitzenhofer%22,%20%22creditlink%22=%3E%22https://www.flickr.com/photos/tambako/4750603032/%22%7D" /></entry></feed>