<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Queer Auntie</title>
		<description></description>
		<link></link>
		<atom:link href="/rss-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>2019 Astrology Big Picture</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5&gt;2019 basics&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major theme of the year is understanding who is in your circle and how to care for each other (north node in cancer). Folks are feeling eager to understand and explore new perspectives and deepen understanding of cultural differences (jupiter in sagittarius). This is a good year to collaborate on creative projects that raise awareness and encourage a compassionate, socially responsible, democratic spirit of solidarity (sextiles of saturn to neptune). This month is ideal for starting commitments on projects and relationships that steadily create lasting, beautiful objects. (mars and uranus in taurus).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/astrology/Zoom-Out-2019.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrology/Zoom-Out-2019.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Astrology Feb 5-25</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5&gt;Companion plants&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003 I started volunteering at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cityslickerfarms.org&quot;&gt;City Slicker Farms,&lt;/a&gt; an urban farm that has been at the forefront of the food justice movement. Back then it was a couple of single-lot farms and a handful of backyard gardens. I often worked alongside &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/essential-urban-farmer/oclc/781618683&quot;&gt;Willow Rosenthal,&lt;/a&gt; who showed me the ropes. At first, I was all fired up to pull every last weed to help the plants grow more efficiently. That’s when Willow taught me about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.farmersalmanac.com/companion-planting-guide-31301&quot;&gt;companion planting,&lt;/a&gt; a practice of creating a habitat by allowing different plants (including “weeds”) to grow next to each other. These plant pairings help each other grow better and protect each other from pests.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/astrology/Circle-Astrology.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrology/Circle-Astrology.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Lantana and Crows</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The air gets crisp with melted grass &lt;br /&gt;
on quiet, hot days in Southern California. &lt;br /&gt;
The sidewalk makes its move to dehydrate &lt;br /&gt;
back to cement powder. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/poetry/Lantana-Crows.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/poetry/Lantana-Crows.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Astro Extras Feb 1-19</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5&gt;the tattoo: an astro activity&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;here’s a little activity for this week. you will need a paper and pen.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/astrology/Astrology-Extra.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrology/Astrology-Extra.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Astrology Feb 1-19</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5&gt;Ask for help. Offer help.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These next couple weeks will be increasingly high energy, and by mid-February everyone is going to be on one. You are in a new place, really feeling yourself, and ready to make something that means something to you, the real you, the dusted-off shoulders you. You might surprise yourself with how much you will be able to accomplish. At the same time, it can be easy to get frenzied. Stay grounded by giving your out-of-this-world grand plans connected a results-oriented project, practical daily routine or be in collaboration with others.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/astrology/Help-Astrology.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrology/Help-Astrology.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>T-shirts and bread</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.queerauntie.com/education/rumi&quot;&gt;Teachers, families and students are fighting for public school education in Oakland, CA.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/education/Student-Help.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/Student-Help.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New-ish</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rumikoshino.com/section/203890-Sculpture-Installation.html&quot;&gt;Rumi Koshino&lt;/a&gt; is an artist and teacher. For three years she has been teaching at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ousd.org/domain/1712&quot;&gt;Oakland High,&lt;/a&gt; where the teachers are probably going to strike this February. I called her a few nights ago and asked how she’s doing.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/education/Rumi.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/Rumi.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>California Public School Crisis</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5&gt;The basic blueprint&lt;/h5&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/education/School-Crisis.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/education/School-Crisis.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Uranus Enters Taurus</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Uranus moves through signs very slowly, in each sign for like 7 or more years… so I like to see how this unfolds. Even though the fateful day of the transition is meaningful and it’s funny you actually can notice the switch, I like to wait and see what we foment.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/astrology/Uranus-Enters-Taurus.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrology/Uranus-Enters-Taurus.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Museum at F.I.T.</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Late April. Around 5:30pm. I’m walking down the street to a see a museum show about high fashion for different body types. Right out in public, in the middle of busy Manhattan, a class of bootcampers side-shuffle from one side of the one-lane street to the other. At any moment, a car could drive through them, or want to drive through them. The instructor shouts commands in a heavy New York accent. I imagined he had been a fire fighter or a cop who survived 9-11 and couldn’t work the job anymore due to PTSD. He decided on a career change: to use his aggressive tenacity to motivate 20-somethings into shape.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/museum/The-Museum-at-FIT.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/museum/The-Museum-at-FIT.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
