<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Queer Auntie Internet Adventure</title>
		<description>If you've thought about it, I have wondered about it.</description>
		<link></link>
		<atom:link href="/rss-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Sugar Hill Museum</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The Sugar Hill Museum, in the Sugar Hill neighborhood of Harlem, is full of interactive materials. Raw wood sticks with frayed bark in a horizontal built-in shelf, some just lying there, others in a natural fiber basket. They seem like props for kids to generate stories and I wondered how it worked. Same with the living room-sized chess board on the floor with toddler-sized chess pieces in the central open gallery space. Keeping track of any chess game would result in a story structure, since it has relationship, motivation, strategy to pull that off with devastating losses and smug victories, and every emotion in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/museum%20review/Sugar-Hill-Museum.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/museum%20review/Sugar-Hill-Museum.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Town Cats</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Town Cats who &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; to own the turf.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s a jukebox of kittens.&lt;br /&gt;
They pee on the mats. Perfume!&lt;br /&gt;
Now that’s the ticket.&lt;br /&gt;
They &lt;strong&gt;start&lt;/strong&gt; to fight the House Cat.&lt;br /&gt;
The big owner invades!&lt;br /&gt;
They pee and have sex. Feline Infection!&lt;br /&gt;
They &lt;strong&gt;realize&lt;/strong&gt; they don’t mind the cars, that much anyways.&lt;br /&gt;
If they &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt; only &lt;strong&gt;get&lt;/strong&gt; Tommy to &lt;strong&gt;stop trying&lt;/strong&gt; an insurrection.&lt;br /&gt;
Bass drum. High hat. Scratch. Crash! Ride.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/poetry/Town-Cats.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/poetry/Town-Cats.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>When It’s Just Dark</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Sheets of hot tin roof go “waeahwaehhhweeaahhh,” a shimmering saw. Fleet-footed. A piece of cake pulled from the one cooling in the windah. Crumblings onto the unlit grass shards. Running through backyards in just the 1950s just a boy with a slingshot in yer pocket sayin’ “gee whiz” the neck snaps back, trachea bent into a dent by a cotton cord not always strung with clothes usually but not always. His birthright chances scatter like cat-eyes, surround where his spine lies. Their glassy flecks currying God-given favors, oven lives, clotheslines, boy oh boy cake freaks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/poetry/When-It-s-Just-Dark.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/poetry/When-It-s-Just-Dark.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>God’s Back (Again)</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;“Hey there believers, it’s Angel Rafael here, with another vlog post. This time I’m in The Brooklyn Public Library. It’s the middle of the night. I was sent here to deliver these stone tablets with news from this one god named Rebenca. She’s the one who helps you get tax breaks out of the blue. And avoid meter maids. One time she made a meter maid trip and fall while he was ticketing a person who just lost their job. That Rebenca! She watches soaps and drinks whiskey sours all day. Then goes on walks through the galactic rainforest. Rebenca helped write three of the original commandments. Oh and she gives out EXTRA GOOD multiple orgasms to everyone, male or female, who is pure of heart. She throws parties every time the moons 3 galaxies away get full, which is most months. Oh Rebenca! Always wears these wild purple velvet gowns with three gemstones dangling on each shoulder pad. This week it’s rubies.’&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/comedy/Commandments.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comedy/Commandments.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Five Alive</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;When Lucia saw the one where Bugs cut carrots into his own cauldron, the one he was being cooked in, she went to the kitchen and got a bag of carrots from the bottom drawer of the fridge and a knife from the wooden silverware drawer. On the sofa, she cut the carrots into disks and pretended to be boiled alive while singing like Bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/fiction/Five-Alive.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/fiction/Five-Alive.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
